Guide to the Steffi Domike Papers, 1946-2009 AIS.1997.20
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- The River Ran Red, VII.
  - Funding, 1.
    - Pennsylvania Humanities Council Continuing Media Grant, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Donnet Fund, Inc., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Mid-Atlantic Region Media Arts Fellowships, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Legislative Initiative Grant, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Fundraising Update Mailing, February 1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Joseph Beirne Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - The River Ran Red Budget Summary (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Pennsylvania Humanities Council Blank Forms (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Agreement between Co-Editors of Book (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Application to Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission, Mon Valley Initiative (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Snee-Reinhardt Charitable Foundation (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Clippings Regarding Women Owned Companies (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Potential Funders for The River Ran Red Study Guide (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Possible Funders Information (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Draft Letter and Generic Executive Summary for Potential Funders in Labor (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - IRS Correspondence with Pittsburgh Filmmakers and Mon Valley Media Regarding Income Tax Exemption (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Homestead Fundraising (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Photograph Costs (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Fundraising Labor Mailing List (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The River Ran Red, Movie production, 2.
    The files in this subseries include resumes and credentials of several of the actors and crew members of The River Ran Red documentary. Other documents include information on research, film logs and on-site scene filming, and details on the sound recordings used in the movie. Many of the articles in the research section are repeated, with different notes and highlighting depending on the topic of the folder.
    New Materials added October 2011.
    - Credits List, Plus and EDL Printout with Computer Disks (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Crew List (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cinematographers (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Prop Contributor List (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Recording Narration, Blair Brown (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Crew Resumes (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Actors' Resumes (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Narrator Blair Brown Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Artist Fred Carlson, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Artist Charles Ingram, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Artists Stacey Innerst and Bob Qualters, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - New World Records-- Yankee Brass Band Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Musician Neely Bruce Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Archie Green and Homestead Strike Songs (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Lists and Notes for Music (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Music Rights Clearance (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Sheet Music (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Musician Mike Sweeney's Cassette (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Sound Effects (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Blank Release Forms for Image and Property (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Scene Location Authorization, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Clayton and River Shoots, Production Schedules (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Courthouse and Jail Correspondence Photographs and Negatives (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Homestead Dead and Wounded Gravesite Photographs (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Scotland Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Train Footage (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - PBS Program Producer's Handbook (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - New York Voice-Over Trip (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Pittsburgh Filmmakers (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Distribution Plan (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Foundation Pages (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Corporate Originals (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Original The River Ran Red Support Letters (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Graphics and Greater Pittsburgh (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Debolt and Homestead Fires, April 11-13, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Edit Decision Lists (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Field Logs (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Film Logs and Videotaped Stills (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Lab Reports (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Log Sheet Blank Forms (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Edit Logs in Camera Roll Order (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
    - Video Logs/Stills in Video Real Order (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Logs for Filmed Stills (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
    - Audio and Sound Effects Log (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Script Copies with Edit Notes and the Homestead Demolition Research (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - New Material Added, 2011
      - Camera and Sound Logs, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Draft Script, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Draft Script, January 1992 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Draft Script, April 1992 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Draft Script, December 1992 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Draft Script, January 1993 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Draft Script for Voice Overs, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - Final Draft Script with Narrator Recording Notes, 1993 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - Interview of and Correspondence with Harold Ruttenberg, 1991-1992 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - Interviews of Homestead Retirees, 1991 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      - Interview of Monsignor Charles Owen Rice, 1991 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      - Project Summary as Original Title, "Monongahela Morning", undated (Box 73, Folder 12)
      - Review Published in the Public Historian, 1993 (Box 73, Folder 13)
      - Shooting Logs, 1991-1992 (Box 73, Folder 14)
      - Sound Logs, 1993 (Box 73, Folder 15)
      - Study Guide, 1994 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Research, 3.
    This section contains materials collected while researching for The River Ran Red. These documents were accumulated from a variety of archives and libraries across the country and include essays that appear in books regarding the Homestead strike, late-nineteenth century labor issues, and the steel industry. Also present are copies of newspaper articles from 1892 which discuss the Homestead conflict.
    - Rivers of Steel (Box 6, Volume 1)
    - The Nation Review of The Killing Floor (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Play Steel/City, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Investigation Articles, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Senate Investigation Articles, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - E. C. Kirkland, "Dream and Thought in the Business Community", 1860-1900 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Pictorial History of American Labor by William Cahn (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - American Labor by M.B. Schnapper (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Parks: A Part of Pittsburgh by the Citizen's Committee on City Planning of Pittsburgh, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Homestead: The Households of a Mill Town by Margaret Byington (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Pittsburgh Index, 1903-1904 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Louis Sullivan and the Chicago School by Nancy Frazer (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - J.J. McIlyar: an Autobiography (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Steel Bibliography by Bob Noble, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - History Books' Account of Strike (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Cloud by Day Photographs (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - Fort Frick or The Siege of Homestead by Myron Stowell (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - History of the First Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Inside History of the Carnegie Steel Company (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Emma Goldman in America by Alice Wexler (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Wage Earning Pittsburgh, ed. Paul Underwood Kellogg (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Who Built America? American Social History Project (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Tribune Almanac, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Labor Poems (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Account of the Homestead Strike by Robert P. Dickson (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Strikers, Communists, Tramps, and Detectives by Allan Pinkerton (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Pinkertons by James D. Horan (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - London by Dore and Jerrold (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - The Lockout, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Labor Rights, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Legal Articles, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Legal Articles (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Management Articles, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Militia Articles (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Negotiations, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Pinkertons (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
    - Reflections After the Strike (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Strike Activities (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Technology/Economics (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Finch and Other Women (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Steel Workers Organizing Committee (S.W.O.C.) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - George Meany Labor Archives, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Chicago Historical Society, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - George Eastman House, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Braddock Library, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Bill Gaughan Collection, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Carnegie Museum's Swank Photographs, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - John Gates Coke Photographs, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Hagley Museum and Library, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Lewis Hine Images, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - American Social History Project and National Police Gazette Image, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Bettman Commercial Archives, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Drake Well Museum Oil Well Image, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Johnstown Area Heritage Association Steel Mill Footage, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Library of Congress, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Pennsylvania Room Photographs from Carnegie Library (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Andrew Carnegie Birthplace Museum in Dunfermline, Scotland (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Carnegie Library in Homestead (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Carnegie Mellon University Archives (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Culver Commercial Archives Pictures (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Carnegie Music Hall Archives in New York (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Frick Archives (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Frick Archives (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Recorder of Deeds (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Pittsburgh Survey Photographs from the University of Pittsburgh Falk Library (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Hillman Library and Archives, University of Pittsburgh (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Photographs of Lowell, Massachusetts (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Museum of the City of New York (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - National Archives and Records Administration (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - National Park Service (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - New York Historical Society (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - New York Municipal Archives (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - New York Public Library (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Pattee Library Historical Collections and Labor Archives, Pennsylvania State University (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - New York Society Library (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Pittsburgh History and Landmarks (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Rare Book Search Information (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Smithsonian and Hirschorn (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvania State Archives (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Steamship Society of America (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - UCIR, University of Pittsburgh Photographic Center (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Andrew Carnegie (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Homestead Library research (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Library Research (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Homestead Related Articles (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Homestead, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
    - Samuel Gompers Letters (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Randy Harris Photographs (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - B.L.H. Dabbs (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Black Workers (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Pastor McIlyar Articles (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Articles Regarding the Amalgamated Association #2 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Mock Amalgamated Document Articles (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Articles on the Amalgamated Association #1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Frick Assassination Attempt Articles (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Alexander Berkman Articles (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Andrew Carnegie Articles (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - John McLuckie (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Thomas Crawford Article (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Hugh O'Donnell (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Henry Clay Frick Articles (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Ethnic and Unskilled Labor Articles (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Irish World and Industrial Labor Articles (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Chicago Times from Chicago Historical Society (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Harper's Weekly Photographs (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Harper's Weekly, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - McClure's Magazine Photographs and Articles (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - McClure's Magazine, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Pennsylvania Magazine Correspondence and Article (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - The Pittsburgh Dispatch, July 6, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Pittsburgh Press Photographs (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Pittsburgh Press, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Scribner's, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Utica Saturday Globe, July, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Pittsburg Leader, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 41-42)
    - Frank Leslie's Weekly, 1892-1893 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - The Iron Trade Review, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - The Engineering and Mining Journal, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - The Iron Age, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - The World, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
    - London Times and Newspaper Research (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Labor Tribune, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - New York Times, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - New York Herald, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Pittsburgh Commercial Gazette, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Pittsburgh Post, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Pittsburgh Post and Pittsburgh Evening Telegraph, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Homestead Local News, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh Times, 1882, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Pittsburgh Dispatch, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Trade Union of Pittsburgh and Allegheny, Their History, 1895 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous News Clippings, 1892 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Aftermath of the Homestead Strike (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Press and Premiere, 4.
    This subseries details the premiere of The River Ran Red documentary and the reviews of the movie. Included are news clippings, press releases, and Homestead Centennial Committee information contributing to the awareness of the Homestead strike. Also present are merchandise requests and a River Ran Red t-shirt.
    - Advertisements, Press Releases, and Programs for The River Ran Red, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Publicity Photographs (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - The River Ran Red Ariel Dorfman, LaRoche, and Miscellaneous Press (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Homestead Steel Strike Centennial Activities, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Homestead Centennial Committee Resumes (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Homestead Consultants and Advisor's Confirmation (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Homestead 1892 Centennial Committee's Cultural Committee (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Clippings on the Homestead Strike, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Press Kit Originals, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Press Packet for Newsletter Mailing (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Press File (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Press List (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Letters of Support, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Community Contacts (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Letters from Advisors (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Labor Studies Forum, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Mailing List for Direct Mail Compiled by Susan Gross (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Direct Mail Follow-Up (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Premiere Materials, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Program Advertisements (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The River Ran Red Premiere Ticket Reservations (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Screening Invitation, November 11, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Labor's Corner Homestead Show, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - The River Ran Red Teachers' Guide (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Comments on Project and Harrisburg Legislator List, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Labor Management Network, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Iron and Steel Technology Change Articles (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Reviews and News Clippings (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Published Summaries and Reviews, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - The River Ran Red, Book material, 5.
    This subseries contains information regarding the book created from the documentary. Files include a bibliography, book orders, and reviews. Photographs used in the book can be found in Series VIII.
    - Book Bibliography (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Letters and Proposal Confirmations for Book (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Materials for Book (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Book Notes (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Book Sidebars (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Book Reviews, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - The River Ran Red T-Shirt (Box 10, Item 1)
- Committees, Rallies, and Strikes, 1977-1984; VIII.
  This series documents various labor related committees, rallies, and strikes in the western Pennsylvania region.
  - Women of Steel, 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Steelworkers Fight Back, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Rally in the Valley, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - USX Clairton Coke Works USWA Local 1557, 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Steelworkers Stand Up Press Conference, May 31, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - USWA Rally at Station Square, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Tri-State Meeting at Turtle Creek, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - J&L Coke Works, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - ICU Conference, William Penn Hotel in Pittsburgh, May 14, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jobs, Peace, and Freedom March, August, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - St. Peter's Church Steelworker Food Bank, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Mon Valley Unemployed Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
  - Ed Asner at Rainbow Kitchen, January 19, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Workers' Power in Chicago, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Coal Miners Rally in Pittsburgh, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Mellon Bank Rally in Homestead, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Support our Neighborhood Action Coalition Giant Eagle Rally, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Comeback Conference (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Mondale/Ferraro Presidential Rally in Boston, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Westinghouse Air Brake Company Strike (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Pittsburgh Gold and Silver Exchange March Against Apartheid in South Africa, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Teamsters for a Democratic Union (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Women's Peace Encampment in Seneca, New York, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Thomas Merton Center, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Grand Concourse Strike (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Audio/Visual Materials, IX.
  This series contains video and audio cassettes and reel to reel film recording Domike's work on Labor's Corner, The River Ran Red, Women of Steel, Life Without Father, Niccaribe, and Out of This Furnace: A Walking Tour. Also included are various reports and interviews regarding Pittsburgh and the steel industry, such as those on the Steel Valley Authority. Reports about union strikes at and the United Mine Workers are also present. It should be noted that many of the titles are only a brief synopsis or part of what may be written on a case and/or its item, as many items include detailed descriptions and further information than a title.
  - Labor's Corner, 1.
    This subseries contains episodes of the weekly half-hour television program Labor's Corner which was produced by Domike and discussed issues concerning Pittsburgh area workers and labor unions. The show filmed sixty episodes from 1987-1990 and appeared on Pittsburgh public television station, WQEX.
    - Labor's Corner Videos, 30 Betacam (Box 13, Video 001-030)
    - Labor's Corner Videos, 14 Betacam, 4 VHS, 3 3/4" Umatic (Box 14, Video 031-051)
    - Labor's Corner Videos, 30 Betacam, 1 VHS, 2 UMATIC (Box 76, Video 810-842)
    - Labor's Corner
      Interview conducted by Mark McCollough with Peter Gilmore and Gary Huck regarding Fred Wright.
  - The River Ran Red, 2.
    The videos in this subseries are all part of the production of The River Ran Red documentary. Included are raw footage, stock footage, voice overs, and the finished edit of the film.
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 5 Betacam, 2 VHS, 4 3/4" Umatic (Box 15, Video 052-062)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 10 3/4" Umatic (Box 16, Video 063-072)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 30 Betacam (Box 17, Video 073-093)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 20 Betacam, 5 3/4" Umatic (Box 18, Video 103-127)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 10 3/4" Umatic (Box 19, Video 128-137)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 10 3/4" Umatic (Box 20, Video 138-147)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 10 3/4" Umatic (Box 21, Video 148-157)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 10 3/4" Umatic (Box 22, Video 158-167)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 10 3/4" Umatic (Box 23, Video 168-177)
    - The River Ran Red Videos, 1 3/4" Tape (Box 58, Video 715)
  - Women of Steel, 3.
    This subseries contains all of the footage, audio, interviews and stock images used to create the 1985 documentary Women of Steel. The film follows a group of women during their time as steelworkers and their lives after the collapse of the steel industry. Women of Steel has won numerous first place awards from The National Commission on Working Women Broadcast Awards, The National Educational Film Festival, and the Tucson Women's Video Festival.
    - Women of Steel Videos, 9 3/4" Umatic (Box 24, Video 178-189)
    - Women of Steel Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 25, Video 190-201)
    - Women of Steel Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 26, Video 202-213)
    - Women of Steel Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 27, Video 214-225)
    - Women of Steel Videos, 11 3/4" Umatic, 2 VHS (Box 28, Video 226-238)
    - Women of Steel Videos, 7 VHS (Box 29, Video 243-250)
    - Women of Steel Videos, 1 3/4" Tape (Box 58, Video 716)
  - Life Without Father, 4.
    The contents of this series are a variety of formats of tape documenting the creation of the Life Without Father documentary. Much of the footage is of the interviews of the women featured in the film, but raw footage and the end product are present as well. The final documentary follows three single mothers by choice. The documentary underwent several name changes, with most tapes being labeled SMC (Single Mothers Coalition), but all of the items in this series all pertain to Life Without Father.
    - Life Without Father Videos, 2 VHS, 4 3/4" Umatic (Box 29, Video 239-242, 251-252)
    - Life Without Father Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 30, Video 253-264)
    - Life Without Father Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 31, Video 265-276)
    - Life Without Father Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 32, Video 277-288)
    - Life Without Father Videos, 12 3/4" Umatic (Box 33, Video 289-300)
    - Life Without Father Videos, 6 3/4" Umatic, 2 VHS (Box 34, Video 301-309)
    - Life Without Father Videos, 1 3/4" Tape (Box 58, Video 717)
  - Nicarribe, 5.
    This subseries holds the extensive documentation of the production of Niccaribe. This documentary was filmed in Nicaragua and focuses on the lands and people of the Atlantic coast, also known as Niccaribe. Interviews about the community, people's heritage, the role of the church, and politics of the 'Niccaribe' area are featured. The interviewees discuss the attempted revolution and military oppression they experienced as well.
    - Nicarribe Videos, 5 Betacam, 1 VHS, 2 3/4" Umatic (Box 34, Video 310-317)
    - Nicarribe Videos, 30 Betacam (Box 35, Video 318-347)
    - Nicarribe Videos, 14 Betacam, 1 3/4" Umatic (Box 36, Video 348-362)
    - Nicarribe Videos, 9 VHS, 5 3/4" Umatic (Box 37, Video 363-376)
    - Nicarribe Videos, 11 3/4" Umatic (Box 38, Video 377-387)
    - Nicarribe Videos, 2 VHS, 9 Betacam, 5 3/4" Umatic (Box 39, Video 388-391)
  - Out of This Furnace: A Walking Tour of Thomas Bell's Novel, 6.